"Advanced Threat Defense"

"Comprehensive Threat Shield"

"Ultimate Spam Blocker"

"Effortless Integration"

"Multilingual Support"

"Works in China"

"Top-tier CAPTCHA Service"

"100% GDPR Compliant"

"Top-Tier Support"

"Privacy-Compliant Captcha"

"Great reCaptcha Alternative"

MTCaptcha - Captcha Plugin Privacy Policy
=========================================

Effective date: September 1, 2024

Welcome to MTCaptcha("MTCaptcha", "us", "we", or "our"). The MTCaptcha Captcha Plugin Service ("Captcha Service") is here to protect you the end user, and the operations of websites and services that incorporate this captcha service, to better detect and prevent undesired access or attacks by automated systems or bots.

This page informs you of our policies regarding the collection, use and disclosure of personal data when you use our Captcha Service and the choices you have associated with that data. We do not collect or store any information from this Captcha Service that can identify you individually and any potential personally identifiable information (such as network IPs address) are fully anonymized. We also guarantee that no usage information from this Captcha Service will be shared or sold to any parties other than for the purpose of delivering and improving this Captcha Service to prevent undesired bot access.

By using the Captcha Service, you agree to the collection and use of information in accordance with this policy. Unless otherwise defined in this Privacy Policy, the terms used in this Privacy Policy have the same meanings as in our Terms and Conditions, accessible from https://www.mtcaptcha.com

### DEFINITIONS

* **Captcha Service**
* Captcha Service is a automation (bot) detection and prevention (captcha) widget (plugin) and related APIs and capabilities operated under https://www.mtcaptcha.com https://service.mtcaptcha.com/mtcv1/ and https://service2.mtcaptcha.com/mtcv1/ by MTCaptcha and embedded in client websites and client services.
* **Personal Data**
* Personal Data means data about a living individual who can be identified from those data (or from those and other information either in our possession or likely to come into our possession).  

* **Usage Data**
* Usage Data is data collected automatically either generated by the use of the Captcha Service or from the Captcha Service infrastructure itself (for example, the duration of a page visit).  

* **Cookies**
* Cookies are small files stored on your device (computer or mobile device).  

* **Data Controller**
* Data Controller means the natural or legal person who (either alone or jointly or in common with other persons) determines the purposes for which and the manner in which any personal information are, or are to be, processed.
* For the purpose of this Privacy Policy, we are a Data Controller of your Personal Data.  

* **Data Processors (or Service Providers)**
* Data Processor (or Service Provider) means any natural or legal person who processes the data on behalf of the Data Controller.
* We may use the Services of various Service Providers in order to process collected data more effectively.  

* **Data Subject (or User)**
* Data Subject is any living individual who is using our Captcha Service and is the subject of Personal Data.

#### **Data Privacy Framework**

‍Sun Spray Technology LLC dba MTCaptcha ("MTCaptcha") complies with the EU-U.S. Data Privacy Framework (EU-U.S. DPF), the UK Extension to the EU-U.S. DPF, and the Swiss-U.S. Data Privacy Framework (Swiss-U.S. DPF) as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce.  MTCaptcha has been certified to the U.S. Department of Commerce that it adheres to the EU-U.S. Data Privacy Framework Principles (EU-U.S. DPF Principles) with regard to the processing of personal data received from the European Union in reliance on the EU-U.S. DPF and from the United Kingdom (and Gibraltar) in reliance on the UK Extension to the EU-U.S. DPF.  MTCaptcha has been certified to the U.S. Department of Commerce that it adheres to the Swiss-U.S. Data Privacy Framework Principles (Swiss-U.S. DPF Principles) with regard to the processing of personal data received from Switzerland in reliance on the Swiss-U.S. DPF.  If there is any conflict between the terms in this privacy notice and the EU-U.S. DPF Principles and/or the Swiss-U.S. DPF Principles, the Principles shall govern.  To learn more about the Data Privacy Framework (DPF) program, and to view our certification, please visit [https://www.dataprivacyframework.gov/](https://www.dataprivacyframework.gov/).

**Scope:  
**MTCaptcha adheres to the EU-U.S. DPF Principles with respect to personal data of individuals in the European Economic Area member states, the United Kingdom (and Gibraltar) and to the Swiss-U.S. DPF Principles with respect to the personal data of individuals in Switzerland ("Covered Individuals") processed by Sun Spray Technology LLC DBA MTCaptcha as part of providing our Services ("Personal Data").

**Data processed:  
**MTCaptcha provides cloud security services that may be included in other websites and apps. In providing these services, MTCaptcha seeks to minimize collection and retention of data, and maintains no long-term data about End Users of MTCaptcha services, but may process the following Personal Data of Covered Individuals in the United States:  
Communications metadata (e.g. information on originating IP address (anonymized while storing) or other identifier, date and time of interaction);  
Contact information for our customers and their employees with access to the Services, and similar registered user data; and  
Service support email information (contact detail for individuals initiating the support request and any other personal data shared as part of the support request).

**Purposes for which data is used:  
**MTCaptcha may use Personal Data for providing, managing, supporting, deploying, enhancing, or improving our services, as otherwise instructed by the MTCaptcha customer or other data controller who transmitted, received, or stored the data, or in accordance with contractual requirements. MTCaptcha may also use Personal Data for other purposes for which the customer or other data controller has obtained the relevant Covered Individual’s consent.

**Inquiries and complaints:  
**If you are a Covered Individual and believe that MTCaptcha maintains your Personal Data within the scope of our EU-U.S. DPF, the UK Extension to the EU-U.S. DPF, or Swiss-U.S. DPF certifications, you may submit any privacy or data use concerns concerning such data by emailing [\[email protected\]](https://www.mtcaptcha.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection) or by mail to: Sun Spray Technologies LLC **‍**2254 Mora Pl #202 Mountain View, CA 94040, USA Attention: Privacy  
MTCaptcha will respond within 45 days of receiving the communication. If you have an unresolved privacy or data use concern that we have not addressed satisfactorily, please contact our U.S.-based third party dispute resolution provider (free of charge) at [https://www.jamsadr.com/DPF-Dispute-Resolution](https://www.jamsadr.com/DPF-Dispute-Resolution)If neither MTCaptcha nor our U.S.-based third party dispute resolution provider resolves your complaint, you may have the possibility to engage in binding arbitration as provided under the Data Privacy Framework Program (See Data Privacy Framework website).

**Third parties who may receive Personal Data:  
**MTCaptcha may disclose Personal Data to its affiliates, as well as to a limited number of third-party business partners, service providers, vendors, suppliers and other contractors (collectively, "Service Providers") for the purpose of assisting us in providing, managing, deploying, enhancing, or improving our services. MTCaptcha maintains contracts with these MTCaptcha affiliates and Service Providers restricting their access, use and disclosure of Personal Data in compliance with our Data Privacy Framework obligations, and MTCaptcha may be liable if such parties fail to meet those obligations and we are responsible for the event giving rise to the damage. We also may share or disclose Personal Data to the extent that the customer or other data controller has obtained the relevant Covered Individual's consent.

**Your rights to access, to limit use, and to limit disclosure:  
**Covered Individuals have rights to access their stored Personal Data and to limit its use and disclosure. With our Data Privacy Framework certification, MTCaptcha has committed to respect those rights. If you are an Covered Individual and you wish to request access to or to limit use or disclosure of your Personal Data, please contact us by email to [\[email protected\]](https://www.mtcaptcha.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection) or by mail to: Sun Spray Technologies LLC **‍**2254 Mora Pl #202 Mountain View, CA 94040, USA Attention: Privacy

‍**U.S. Federal Trade Commission enforcement:  
**MTCaptcha’s commitments under the Data Privacy Framework are subject to the investigatory and enforcement powers of the United States Federal Trade Commission or the applicable United States authorized statutory body.

**Compelled disclosure:  
**MTCaptcha may be required to disclose Personal Data in response to lawful requests by public authorities, or administrative or judicial processes, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements.

### INFORMATION COLLECTION AND USE

We collect several different types of information for various purposes to provide and improve our Captcha Service to you.

### TYPES OF DATA COLLECTED

#### Personal Data

While using our Captcha Service, we will not collect any information that may directly or indirectly identify you personally ("Personal Data"). Any data generated by the system that may indirectly identify you (such as network IP addresses) are anonymized so it can no longer be Personally Identifiable. Cookies are used by the Captcha Service but do not contain any identifiers or tracking that can be used directly or indirectly as Personal Identifiers

#### Usage Data

We may collect information on how the Captcha Service is accessed and used ("Usage Data"). This Usage Data may include information such as your browser type, browser version, the interactions with the Captcha Service, the time and date of your visit, the time spent, and other diagnostic data.

#### Tracking & Cookies Data

We use cookies and similar technologies to hold certain information and to support the Captcha Service in detecting automation and bot behaviour. We do not use cookies to track individual usage activity on our Captcha Service.

Cookies are files that contains a small amount of data. Cookies can be generated on the device and or sent to your browser from a website and stored on your device. Other technologies are also used such as tags and scripts to collect information (non Personal Data) used to improve and analyse our Captcha Service.

You can instruct your browser to refuse all cookies or to indicate when a cookie is being sent. However, if you do not accept cookies, you may not be able to use some or all portions of our Captcha Service.

Examples of Cookies we use:

* **Device Verification Cookie.** We use Device Verification Cookie to check the accuracy of your browser type.
* **Transaction Cookie.** We use Transaction Cookie to maintain correct transition and flow of the Captcha Service.

### USE OF DATA

MTCaptcha uses the collected data for various purposes:

* To provide and maintain our Captcha Service
* To provide customer support
* To gather analysis or valuable information so that we can improve our Captcha Service
* To monitor the usage of our Captcha Service
* To detect, prevent and address technical issues
* To provide usage audit and reporting to client website operators that incorporates our Captcha Service

MTCaptcha will not use the collected data for:

* Reselling of data for profit
* User profiling or advertisement and marketing
* Reselling of Client Website usage data or usage analytics

### LEGAL BASIS FOR PROCESSING PERSONAL DATA UNDER THE GENERAL DATA PROTECTION REGULATION (GDPR)

If you are from the European Economic Area (EEA), MTCaptcha legal basis for collecting and using the personal information described in this Privacy Policy depends on the Personal Data we collect and the specific context in which we collect it.

MTCaptcha Captcha Service do not record any Personal Data and therefore will not process your Personal Data:

### RETENTION OF DATA

Our Captcha Service will not retain your Personal Data. Our Captcha Service will retain Usage Data only for as long as is necessary for the purposes set out in this Privacy Policy. We will retain and use Usage Data to the extent necessary to comply with our legal obligations (for example, if we are required to retain data to comply with applicable laws), resolve disputes and enforce our legal agreements and policies.

MTCaptcha will also retain Usage Data for internal analysis purposes and to strengthen the security or to improve the functionality of our Captcha Service.

### TRANSFER OF DATA

Usage Data may be transferred to - and maintained on - computers located outside of your state, province, country or other governmental jurisdiction where the data protection laws may differ from those of your jurisdiction.

If you are located outside Ireland or European Union and choose to provide information to us, please note that we transfer the data to Ireland and European Union countries and process it there.

Your consent to this Privacy Policy followed by your submission of such information represents your agreement to that transfer.

MTCaptcha will take all the steps reasonably necessary to ensure that any retained data is treated securely and in accordance with this Privacy Policy and no transfer of Usage Data will take place to an organisation or a country unless there are adequate controls in place including the security of such data

### DISCLOSURE OF DATA

### BUSINESS TRANSACTION

If MTCaptcha is involved in a merger, acquisition or asset sale, your Usage Data may be transferred. We will provide notice before your Usage Data is transferred and becomes subject to a different Privacy Policy.

### DISCLOSURE FOR LAW ENFORCEMENT

Under certain circumstances, MTCaptcha may be required to disclose Usage Data if required to do so by law or in response to valid requests by public authorities (e.g. a court or a government agency).

### LEGAL REQUIREMENTS

MTCaptcha may disclose your Usage Data in the good faith belief that such action is necessary to:

* To comply with a legal obligation
* To protect and defend the rights or property of MTCaptcha
* To prevent or investigate possible wrongdoing in connection with the Captcha Service
* To protect the personal safety of users of the Captcha Service or the public
* To protect against legal liability

### SECURITY OF DATA

The security of your data is important to us but remember that no method of transmission over the Internet or method of electronic storage is 100% secure. While we strive to use commercially acceptable means to protect all Usage Data, we cannot guarantee its absolute security.

### OUR POLICY ON "DO NOT TRACK" SIGNALS UNDER THE CALIFORNIA ONLINE PROTECTION ACT (CALOPPA)

We do not support Do Not Track ("DNT"). Do Not Track is a preference you can set in your web browser to inform websites that you do not want to be tracked.

You can enable or disable Do Not Track by visiting the Preferences or Settings page of your web browser.

### YOUR DATA PROTECTION RIGHTS UNDER THE GENERAL DATA PROTECTION REGULATION (GDPR)

If you are a resident of the European Economic Area (EEA), you have certain data protection rights. MTCaptcha Catpcha Service aims to take reasonable steps to allow you to correct, amend, delete or limit the use of your Personal Data.

If you wish to be informed about what Personal Data we hold about you (we do not hold any Personal Data from the Captcha Service) and if you want it to be removed from our systems, please contact us.

In certain circumstances, you have the following data protection rights:

* **The right to access, update or delete the information we have on you.** Whenever made possible, you can access, update or request deletion of your Personal Data directly within your account settings section. If you are unable to perform these actions yourself, please contact us to assist you.
* **The right of rectification.** You have the right to have your information rectified if that information is inaccurate or incomplete.
* **The right to object.** You have the right to object to our processing of your Personal Data.
* **The right of restriction.** You have the right to request that we restrict the processing of your personal information.
* **The right to data portability.** You have the right to be provided with a copy of the information we have on you in a structured, machine-readable and commonly used format.
* **The right to withdraw consent.** You also have the right to withdraw your consent at any time where MTCaptcha relied on your consent to process your personal information.

Please note that we may ask you to verify your identity before responding to such requests.

You have the right to complain to a Data Protection Authority about our collection and use of your Personal Data. For more information, please contact your local data protection authority in the European Economic Area (EEA).

### SERVICE PROVIDERS

We may employ third party companies and individuals to facilitate our Captcha Service ("Service Providers"), provide the Captcha Service on our behalf, perform Captcha Service-related services or assist us the analysis of how our Captcha Service is used.

These third parties have access to your Usage Data only to perform these tasks on our behalf and are obligated not to disclose or use it for any other purpose.

### ANALYTICS

We may use third-party Service Providers to monitor and analyse the use of our Captcha Service. Usage of any such Service Providers will also comply with this Privacy Policy, which will only retain Usage Data and do not track or retain any Personal Data.

### BEHAVIORAL REMARKETING

MTCaptcha will not use remarketing services to advertise on third party websites to you after you visited our Captcha Service.

### PAYMENTS

MTCaptcha will not provide paid products and/or services to end users as part of this Captcha Service.

### LINKS TO OTHER SITES

This Captcha Service will not contain links to other sites that are not operated by us.

### CHILDREN'S PRIVACY

Our Captcha Service does not address anyone under the age of 18 ("Children").

We do not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from anyone under the age of 18. If you are a parent or guardian and you are aware that your Child has provided us with Personal Data, please contact us. If we become aware that we have collected Personal Data from children without verification of parental consent, we take steps to remove that information from our servers.

### CHANGES TO THIS PRIVACY POLICY

We may update this Captcha Plugin Privacy Policy from time to time. We will notify you of any changes by posting the new Privacy Policy on this page.

We will let you know via prominent notice on our https://www.mtcaptcha.com/, prior to the change becoming effective and update the "effective date" at the top of this Privacy Policy.

You are advised to review this Privacy Policy periodically for any changes. Changes to this Privacy Policy are effective when they are posted on this page.

### CONTACT US

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, please contact us:

* By email: [\[email protected\]](https://www.mtcaptcha.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)
* By visiting this page on our website: [https://www.mtcaptcha.com/contact](https://www.mtcaptcha.com/contact)

GDPR Compliant Captcha for the Enterprise  

--------------------------------------------

.png)

Resources

Copyright © 2024 Sun Spray Technologies LLC

By clicking **“Accept”**, you agree to our use of cookies. We use cookies to provide you with a great experience and to help our website run effectively.
